Ahh... if you're looking for that mansion...
...نعم إن كنت تبحث عن ذلك القصر
just keep going up this hill.
فواصل طريقك عبر ذلك المرتفع
I see. Thank you.
فهمت، شكرًا
You're welcome.
العفو
Roses...
...الزهرة
This almost seems like Sleeping Beauty's castle.
يبدو شبيهًا بقلعة (الجميلة النائمة)
My name is Anna... Anna Liebert.
اسمي (آنا)... (آنا ليبرت)
Good luck, Mr. Detective.
حظًا موفقًا، سيدي المحقق
If something were to happen to you....
...إن حدث أي شيء لك
When I think of that...
...حين أفكر في ذلك
I...
...أنا
I feel the same way your mother did, so...
أشعر بنفس ما شعرت به أمك
Anna...
(آنا)
Were you dreaming...
هل كنت تحلم؟
Detective Suk?
محقق (سوك)؟
Yeah...
أجل
You're...
...أنت
Lunge.
(لونغي)
An inspector from the German BKA.
محقق من المباحث الفيديرالية الألمانية
BKA?
المباحث الفيديرالية؟
Yeah.
أجل
You don't have to sit up.
لا تتعب نفسك
I didn't come here to arrest you or anything.
لم آت إلى هنا لإلقاء القبض عليك
This is a pretty nice hospital room.
إنها غرفة مستشفى جميلة
The old Czechoslovakian secret police...
الشرطة السرية السابقة لتشيكوسلوفاكيا
I traced all the hospitals they were connected to...
لقد مررتُ على كل المستشفيات التي لها علاقة بهم
and finally ended up here.
وأخيرًا وصلتُ إلى هنا
To think you're receiving such treatment...
بالتفكير في العناية التي تتلقاها من الشرطة السرية
You must be important to them.
فلا بد أنك مهم لديهم
No, I'm just...
...لا، أنا فقط
I already know what happened.
أعرف جيدًا ما حدث
I know about Inspector Zeman's connection to the secret police and his brutal death.
أعرف بأمر المحقق (زيمان) وعلاقته بشرطة تشيكوسلوفاكيا السرية ومقتله البشع
Prague's police chief and two officers were poisoned to death.
رئيس شرطة (براغ) ومعاوناه اللذان سُمِّما حتى الموت
The two agents who were sent to tail you...
العميلان اللذان أرسلا لتتبع أثرك
were found shot to death.
واللذان وُجدا مقتولين
And you're the chief suspect in all the incidents that have taken place.
وأنت المشتبه الأول في كل هذه القضايا المتتالية
Considering all the evidence stacked against you...
بالنظر إلى كل الأدلة الشاهدة ضدك
you're the culprit.
فإنك أنت المجرم
I'm not!
!كلا
I didn't do anything!
!أنا لم أفعل شيئًا
Then could it be Grimmer, the tall, thin man...
فهل يكون المجرم هو (غريمر) الرجل الطويل والنحيل الذي تحدث مع المحقق (زيمان) قبل يوم من مقتله؟
It's not Mr. Grimmer, either!
إنه ليس (غريمر)
He wouldn't do something like that.
هو لن يفعل شيئًا كهذا
In that case, who is the killer?
فمن هو القاتل إذًا؟
You know, don't you?
أنت تعرف صحيح؟
You know who the killer is right?
ألست تعرف من هو القاتل؟
W-What are you talking about?
ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟
If I knew, I wouldn't be in this state.
لو كنت أعرف، لما كنت في هذا الوضع
Deceived by so many people...
خانني أناس كثيرون
set up to take the fall...
حتى جُعلتُ قاتلًا وصرتُ مطلوبًا من الشرطة التي أنتمي إليها
I've had enough of this!
!اكتفيتُ من كل هذا
I don't want to be betrayed anymore!
!لا أريد أن أتعرض للخيانة مجددًا
You're a detective, aren't you?
ألستَ محققًا؟
If you're a detective...
...إن كنتَ محققًا
then you have to calmly dissect the situation.
فيجب أن تحلل الأوضاع بهدوء
Even if it's painful...
ومهما كان ذلك مؤلمًا
you must calmly uncover the truth.
فيجب عليك بهدوء أن تكشف الحقيقة
If you don't want to be betrayed anymore...
...إن أردتَ ألا تتعرض للخيانة أكثر
then start doubting the person you want to doubt the least.
فيجب إذًا أن تشك في أقل الناس مدعاة لذلك
Who gave you permission to see him?
من أذن لك برؤيته؟
I want to see your boss.
أريد رؤية زعيمك
Tell him I want to speak with him about the Rose Mansion.
أخبره أني أريد الحديث معه حول (قصر الزهرة)
He'll want to meet with me.
سيرغب حتمًا في مقابلتي
The Rose Mansion
الفصل 50
Inspector Lunge from the German BKA.
المحقق (لونغي) من المباحث الفيديرالية الألمانية
I'm familiar with your background and personal history.
سمعتُ عنك وعن تاريخك الشخصي
I've also heard rumors about you since the old regime...
وأنا أيضًا كنت أسمع عنك منذ النظام القديم
Colonel Ranke.
عقيد (رانكي)
And now you're practically the head of the old Czechoslovakian secret police.
والآن أنت على رأس الشرطة السرية السابقة لتشيكوسلوفاكيا
it must be quite difficult to control such a large organization these days.
من الصعب اليوم التحكم في منظمة بهذه الضخامة
Thank you for your concern.
شكرًا على اهتمامك
I'm envious that you're able to take such an extended vacation.
أنا أحسدك لأنك استطعت أخذ إجازة طويلة كهذه
Two years ago, the secretary for Senator Borzmann, the German Democratic Party candidate...
منذ عامين، وبسبب تحقيقاتك المتعمقة، فقد أقدم السيناتور (بورزمان) مرشح الحزب الديمقراطي الألماني على الانتحار
You've got to be a little smarter in what you do.
كان عليك أن تكون أكثر حكمة من هذا
You're the fool here.
أنت الأحمق هنا
As long as you seemed legitimate on the surface...
حين كنت تبدو قانونيًا في الواجهة، كنت تستطيع الاستمرار في إخفاء أسرارك
and acted as the president from the shadows.
والتصرف كرئيس لهذا البلد من وراء الظلال
But now, the frightened citizens see you as you really are.
لكن الآن، المواطنون الخائفون ينظرون إليك كما أنت حقًا
I see.
هكذا إذًا
You're a smart one.
أنت شخص ذكي
So, what does a smart man like you want from me?
ما الذي يريده رجل ذكي مثلك مني؟
Well, as you know, I'm not simply on this extended vacation for leisure...
حسنًا، وكما تعلم، فإني لا أمضي عطلتي الطويلة هنا لمجرد الترفيه
I've been searching...
...لقد كنت أبحث
for the existence of true terror.
عن وجود الرعب الحقيقي
There's a possibility that the illusion you created...
هناك احتمال بأن الأوهام التي صنعتَها
may have given birth to the devil itself.
كانت سببًا في ولادة الشيطان نفسه
So this is about the Red Rose Mansion?
إذًا، هل تتحدث عن قصر الزهرة الحمراء؟
I had to investigate quite a bit before I found the mansion...
كان علي أن أتحرى قليلًا قبل عثوري على القصر
because the author has so many pen names.
لأن الكاتب كان لديه كثير من الأسماء المستعارة
"The Monster Without a Name."
"وحش بدون اسم"
By Emil Scherbe.
لمؤلفه: (إيميل سيبي)
Address, an office in an old building in Prague.
العنوان: مكتب في بناية قديمة في (براغ)
Right now, another company is leasing the place.
حاليًا هناك شركة أخرى في المكان
Klaus Poppe's address was listed as an old farmhouse outside the city.
عنوان (كلاوس بوبي) ذُكر على أنه منزل قروي خارج المدينة
It was demolished.
أمر مخيب للآمال
Jakov Vyrobek's was just a rented office, too.
عنوان (يعقوب فاروبيك) هو مجرد مكتب مستأجَر
And...
...إذًا
did you find him?
هل وجدتَه؟
Franz Bonaparta?
فرانز بونابارتا)؟)
What is that mansion?
ما سر ذلك القصر؟
And who is Franz Bonaparta?
ومن هو (فرانز بونابارتا)؟
Every search I run on him comes up with nothing.
كل تحقيق أجريتُه حوله لم يسفر عن شيء
That means he must be under your protection.
وهذا يعني أنه تحت حمايتك
An old Czechoslovakian secret police officer.
ضابط في شرطة تشيكوسلوفاكيا السرية
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
I want to know what you know.
أريد أن أعرف ما تعرف
I don't know anything.
أنا لا أعرف شيئًا
Just that...
...فقط
Just that...?
فقط؟
I've been consciously trying to forget...
...كنت أحاول جديًا أن أنسى
that the mansion ever existed.
بأن ذلك القصر قد وُجد أصلًا
That's why I never did anything about it...
ولذلك لم أفعل شيئًا بشأنه
and it's still there, untouched.
وما زال قائمًا هناك كما هو
In that mansion...
...في ذلك القصر
all the political prisoners and researchers held there vanished one day.
جميع السجناء السياسيين والباحثين اختفوا يومًا ما
That's the story.
هذه هي القصة
What is that wall for?
وماذا عن ذلك الجدار؟
Wall?
الجدار؟
I was inside the mansion a few days ago.
كنتُ داخل القصر منذ بضعة أيام
There was no sign that anyone else had recently been in there.
ولم أجد أثرًا على أن إنسانًا كان فيه مؤخرًا
It was completely abandoned.
إنه مهجور تمامًا
But...
لكن
the north wall on the second floor...
الجدار الشمالي في الطابق الثاني
was built rather hastily, as if to hide something.
بُني فيما يبدو بسرعة، كما لو كان لإخفاء شيء
May I break down that wall?
هل أستطيع هدم ذلك الجدار؟
What are you afraid of, Colonel Ranke?
مم أنت خائف، عقيد (رانكي)؟
You may die.
قد تموت
If we come any closer...
...إن اقتربنا أكثر
we may come face to face with true terror!
!فقد نقف وجهًا لوجه أمام الرعب الحقيقي
Franz Bonaparta...?
فرانز بونابارتا)؟)
That's a nostalgic name.
اسم يثير الحنين
You want cream and sugar in your coffee?
أتريد حليبًا وسكرًا في قهوتك؟
No, black is fine.
لا، سوداء لو سمحت
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
Nothing...
لا شيء
It's just surprising to have a fan of Franz Bonaparta come here...
فقط فاجأني أن يأتي أحد معجبي (فرانز بونابارتا) إلى هنا
I got your address from Moravia Publishing...
أخذتُ عنوانك من دار نشر (مورافيا)
Mr. Sovak, you were Bonaparta's editor when he was still writing, right?
سيد (زوفاك)، أنت كنت ناشر (بونابارتا) حين كان لا يزال يكتب صحيح؟
Yeah.
أجل
But I was only his editor when he was going by the pen name Klaus Poppe.
لكني كنتُ ناشره فقط حين اتخذ الاسم المستعار (كلاوس بوبي)
Would you mind telling me what he was like?
هل تسمح بأن تحدثني عن صفاته أكثر؟
Franz Bonaparta?
فرانز بونابارتا)؟)
He used to have his work-related meetings here in this house.
كان معتادًا على إجراء اجتماعات العمل هنا في هذا البيت
Yes...
أجل، كان يجلس على نفس ذلك الكرسي
He would often play with my daughter in the yard.
كثيرًا ما كان يلعب مع ابنتي في الحديقة
Back then, my daughter said something rather strange...
ويومًا ما قالت ابنتي شيئًا غريبًا
"That man is scary."
"ذلك الرجل مخيف"
My daughter was still little at the time, so she probably doesn't remember anything now.
كانت ابنتي صغيرة آنذاك، لذا أظن أنها لن تتذكر شيئًا الآن
Was he working with the government back then?
هل كان يعمل مع الحكومة في ذلك الوقت؟
Probably.
ربما
I associated with him assuming that he was.
لقد تعاقدتُ معه على أساس أنه يفعل
However, his mannerisms, his way of speaking...
وعمومًا فإن أسلوبه وطريقته في الكلام وملابسه كانت مغايرة للرجال المهمين في حكومة النظام القديم
And he had a gentleness and elegance about him...
وأيضًا فقد كان أنيقًا ولبقًا للغاية
Bonaparta had a master's in psychology and was a practicing psychologist.
لدى (بونابارتا) طبيباه في علم النفس وكان محللًا نفسيًا
He was also a medical doctor.
وهو طبيب في الطب أيضًا
His specialty was brain surgery.
وتخصصه كان جراحة الدماغ
I... I see...
...فـ... فهمت
The last time I saw him was... let's see...
...آخر مرة رأيتُه فيها كانت
I think it was the summer of '81 or '82.
أظن أنها في صيف 1981 أو 1982
Yes, he just suddenly showed up at my house one day...
أجل، لقد ظهر فجأة في بيتي ذات يوم
with a new story...
مع قصة جديدة
He looked somewhat refreshed.
بدا لي منتعشًا بشكل ما
A new story...
قصة جديدة
What kind of story was it?
عن أي شيء كانت تحكي؟
A story about a monster falling in love.
قصة حول وحش وقع في الحب
But it was like a combination of "Beauty and the Beast" and "Sleeping Beauty."
لكنها بدت وكأنها دمج بين (جميلة والوحش) و(الجميلة النائمة)
I rejected it.
لقد رفضتُها
Then, in the doorway just before he left...
وبعدها، وعند الباب قبل أن يغادر
he turned around and said, "How about this one?"
"التفت إلي وقال: "وماذا عن هذه؟
"The Door That Must Never Be Opened."
"الباب الذي لا يجب أن يُفتح أبدًا "
And I asked him...
حينها سألتُه
"So, on the other side of the door do you find paradise..."
هل سنجد جنة وراء الباب؟
"or a monster biding its time?"
أم أن وراءه وحشًا؟
And he said...
...حينها قال
"Since the door must never be opened, there's no story..."
"بما أن الباب لا يجب أن يُفتح أبدًا، فليست هناك قصة"
He laughed, and left.
عندها ضحك وغادر
That was the last time I saw him.
كانت تلك آخر مرة رأيتُه فيها
So, did you learn anything about Bonaparta?
هل علمتَ أي شيء عن (بونابارتا)؟
No, not really...
...لا، ليس تمامًا
Mr. Grimmer, why are you here?
سيد (غريمر)، لماذا أنت هنا؟
I was just thinking what a fine day it is.
فقط أتأمل جمال هذا اليوم
Yeah.
أجل
I knew it!
!كما توقعت
Ah, is this the police?
مرحبًا، الشرطة؟
This is Sovak, I live on Svejk Court.
أنا (زوفاك) وأعيش في ميدان (شفايك)
The guy that just visited me...
الرجل الذي زارني للتو
Apparently...
فيما يبدو
I think he's wanted for a series of murders in Germany.
أظن أنه مطلوب من أجل سلسلة جرائم قتل في ألمانيا
Yeah, he's Japanese... a brain surgeon named Dr. Tenma.
أجل، إنه ياباني، جراح دماغ اسمه الطبيب (تينما)
Ethanol...
كحول
This room reeks of antiseptics.
الغرفة تعبق بروائح المطهرات
Dead...
...موتى
How many...
كم؟
How many people died here?
كم من الناس ماتوا هنا؟
Ten...
عشرة
Twenty...
عشرون
No, more than that...
...لا، أكثر
That woman...
هذه المرأة
The woman from the sketchbook.
نفس المرأة في كتاب الرسمات
Is she the mother of the twins?
أهي والدة التوأمين؟
If we don't hurry, the older kids will take the soccer field.
إن لم نسرع فسيستولي الآخرون على ملعب الكرة
Hurry up, Milos!
!(هيا أسرع، (ميلوش
Y-Yeah.
حسنًا
Go! Counterattack!
!هيا، هجمة مضادة
Crap! Fall back!
!هيا، تقدم
The goal is wide open!
!مرمى الأهداف مفتوح
No... he's gonna score!
!لا، سيسجل
Hey, Milos!
!(ميلوش)
Are you okay, Milos?!
هل أنت بخير، (ميلوش)؟
Hang in there, Milos.
تماسك يا (ميلوش)
Nice defense, Milos!
دفاع جيد يا (ميلوش)
Nice clear!
!أحسنت
You saved a goal!
لقد حميتَ المرمى
From the way he's laughing...
من طريقة ضحكه
he should be all right now...
يبدو أنه بخير الآن
Right, Dr. Tenma?
صحيح؟ طبيب (تينما)
Yeah.
أجل
Mr. Grimmer...
سيد (غريمر)
aren't you going to see Milos and the other boys?
ألن تذهب لرؤية (ميلوش) وبقية الأطفال؟
I understand now why I'm bad at soccer.
فهمتُ الآن لماذا أنا لاعب كرة سيئ
It's about teamwork.
إنه العمل الجماعي
What's going to happen to Detective Jan Suk now?
ما مصير المحقق (يان سوك) الآن؟
He's the prime suspect in this case.
إنه المشتبه الأول في هذه القضية
It's the same thing as being socially blacklisted.
وهذا يكفي ليدخل لائحة المجتمع السوداء
Even if he turns himself in...
حتى وإن سلَّم نفسه
how can we prove his innocence?
فكيف نستطيع إثبات براءته؟
How can we show that the blonde girl left the crime scene?
كيف سنثبت أن الفتاة الشقراء غادرت مسرح الجريمة؟
Suk must be in the same predicament you're in.
سوك) يمر بنفس المأزق الذي أنت فيه)
However, there is one thing...
باستثناء شيء واحد
Goodbye, Dr. Tenma.
الوداع، طبيب (تينما)
Regarding this case...
بخصوص هذه القضية
there's only one person who knows all the details.
هناك شخص واحد فقط يعرف كافة التفاصيل
It's me.
إنه أنا
What do you think?
ما رأيك؟
If I hand this over to the police...
لو أخذتُ هذه إلى الشرطة
This is?!
!هذه
A letter from the serial killer.
رسالة من القاتل المتسلسل
Details that only the killer would know...
تفاصيل لا يمكن أن يعرفها إلا القاتل نفسه
would make a convincing confession, don't you think?
هل ستشكِّل اعترافًا مقنعًا؟
But if you send this to the police, you'll be...
...لكن، إن أرسلتَ هذه إلى الشرطة، فإنك
Grimmer returned to Germany before you even knew it.
غريمر) عاد إلى ألمانيا قبل أن تعرف ذلك)
Even though the police will try to catch him, Grimmer is capable of staying out of their reach.
حتى لو حاول الشرطة اعتقاله، فإن (غريمر) قادر على البقاء بعيدًا عن قبضتهم
Because he used to be an elite spy.
لأنه كان جاسوسًا محترفًا
But you'll be a suspect for the rest of your life, and will always be on the run...
لكن، ستظل مشتبهًا بك طوال حياتك
That's fine.
لا بأس
Because the man named Grimmer never existed in the first place.
لأن الرجل المسمى (غريمر) غير موجود أصلًا
Someone gave him that name out of convenience.
أحدهم أعطاه هذا الاسم
Even if Grimmer is a suspect for the rest of his life...
حتى لو ظل (غريمر) مشتبهًا به طوال حياته
it'd be fine.
فسأكون بخير
Something like that...
هذه هي
Dr. Tenma, what do you think of the decision I made?
طبيب (تينما)، ما رأيك في القرار الذي اتخذتُه؟
Ahh... never mind.
لا تهتم
Forget it.
انسَ الأمر
You're heading to the Rose Mansion now, right?
هل ستتجه الآن إلى قصر الزهرة؟
Y-Yeah.
أجل
You may finally be getting close to your goal, huh?
يبدو أنك أخيرًا تقترب من هدفك
I... I don't know...
لا، لا أدري
Even if I tell you not to be reckless, it won't change anything, will it?
حتى لو طلبتُ منك ألا تتهور، فذلك لن يغير شيئًا
Just...
فقط... لا تمت
Mr. Grimmer...
سيد (غريمر)
The promise we made when we crossed the Czech border...
الوعد الذي قطعناه حين عبرنا حدود التشيك
That if we met again, we'd have another picnic.
أننا حين نلتقي، سنقوم برحلة أخرى
Fishing for rainbow trout, surrounded by beautiful scenery...
،نصطاد السلمون المرقط وسط مناظر رائعة ونتناول الخمر الجيد والجبنة الممتازة
We'll do that again!
سنفعلها حتمًا
I'll always be living in fear of that sound from here on out.
سأظل خائفًا من هذا الصوت بقية حياتي
Give it back!
!توقفا
Ouch! It hurts!
!مؤلم
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
Let me take a look at it.
دعني ألق نظرة
Ouch!
!مؤلم
It's just a scratch.
إنه مجرد خدش
I'll put some antiseptic on it.
سأضع لك مطهرًا
O-Ouch!
!مؤلم
You're a boy, bear with it.
أنت صبي، تحمل ذلك
There.
أجل
You're a strong kid.
أنت فتى قوي
Kenzo Tenma, I presume?
أنت (كينزو تينما)؟
We're the police.
الشرطة
We'd like you to come with us...
نطلب منك أن تأتي معنا